renttoown.org 2017-06-06

# RentToOwn.org Privacy Policy

November 7, 2016

## Purpose of the Privacy Policy.

RentToOwn.org is committed to respecting and protecting your privacy rights, and we created this Privacy Policy to give you (the user) notice of how your private information will (and will not) be used by us in connection with our website (together with its subdomains, content and services). In simplified form (greater detail is below), our policy can be summarized as follows:

  1. We may collect some information on you, but you control how much you share about yourself.
  2. We take your information seriously.
  3. We do not collect information from children under 13 years of age.
  4. Except for your consent, we will not sell or rent your personal information but may share with our vendors, suppliers and contributors in connection with the services you are seeking.
  5. We may aggregate information.
  6. If we use a third party to assist us, they will be bound to protect your information.
  7. If you are outside the United States, you understand and agree that we may store your information in the United States.
  8. In certain legal situations, we may be compelled to disclose your personal information, but we will let you know if that occurs.

## This Privacy Policy applies to the sites where it appears.

This privacy policy applies to how we use your information.

This policy describes how we treat personal information on the websites where it appears (the “Platforms”). By interacting with us, you consent to these practices.

## We collect information from and about you.

We may collect contact information and personal information on the Platforms. For example, we may collect your address when you use the Platforms. We also collect your name, email address and phone number if you register with us.

We may collect information about your device and Internet usage. If or when you use the Platforms, we might collect information from your phone. We may also collect information about the parts of our Platforms you use or third party apps or websites you visit when you leave our Platforms. When you use our app, we may work with third parties who collect information about you.

We may collect other information. For example, we may collect your location using a cellular network location, GPS, browser services, Wi-Fi networks or information you provide. We might look at how often you use the Platforms.

## We collect information in different ways.

We collect information from you passively. For example, we may collect information from your phone, like your UDID. Our vendors might also use scripts or other tools to track your activities on our Platform. They may do this to make sure our Platforms function properly.

We collect information directly from you. For example, we collect information if you register on the Platforms.

We combine information. For example, we may combine information that we have collected offline with information we collect online. Or we may combine information we collect on with information we’ve collected separately. We may also combine information we collect from you with information we receive from third parties.

We may get information about you from third parties. For example, our affiliates or partners may give us information about you. If our Platforms have social media integration, social media platforms may also give us information about you.

## We use information as disclosed and described here.

We use information to administer the Platforms.

We use information to communicate with you about your account or our relationship. We may contact you about our account or feedback. We might also contact you about this Policy or our Terms.

We use information to respond to your requests or questions. For example, we might use your information to respond to your customer feedback.

We use information for security purposes. We may use information to protect our company, our customers, and our websites.

We use information to improve our products and services. We may use your information to make our website and products better. We might use your information to customize your experience with us.

We use information for marketing purposes. For example, we might provide you with information about new products and special offers from us. We might also use your information to serve you ads about products and offers. We might tell you about new features or updates. These might be third party offers or products we think you might find interesting. To manage this, read the choices section below.

We use information as otherwise permitted by law.

## We may share information with third parties.

We will share information with our vendors. These are third parties who perform services on our behalf. For example, we may share information with vendors who send emails for us.

We may share information with any successor to all or part of our business. For example, if part of our business was sold, we may share information as part of that transaction.

We will share information if we think we have to in order to comply with the law or to protect ourselves. For example, we will share information to respond to a court order or subpoena. We may share it if a government agency or investigatory body requests. We might share information when we are investigating potential fraud.

We may share your information with others with whom you have authorized us to share your information.

We may share information for other reasons we may describe to you.

## You have certain choices about sharing and marketing practices.

You can control cookies and tracking tools. Your browser may give you the ability to control cookies or other tracking tools. How you do so depends on the type of tool. Certain browsers can be set to reject browser cookies. To control flash cookies, which we may use on certain websites from time to time, you can go [here.](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) Why? Because you cannot control flash cookies through your browser settings. 

You can opt out of receiving our marketing emails. To stop receiving our promotional emails, follow the instructions in any promotional message you get from us. Even if you opt out of getting marketing messages, we will still send you transactional messages. These include responses to your questions.

Our Do Not Track Policy: Some browsers have “do not track” features that allow you to tell a website not to track you. These features are not all uniform. We do not currently respond to those signals. If you block cookies, certain features on our sites may not work. If you block or reject cookies, not all of the tracking described here will stop.

## Your California privacy rights.

If you reside in California, you have the right to ask us one time each year if we have shared personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make a request, please send us an email at [support@member.renttoown.org](mailto:support@member.renttoown.org) , or write to us at the address listed below. Indicate in your letter that you are a California resident making a “Shine the Light” inquiry.

## These sites and apps are not intended for children.

Our Platforms are meant for adults. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 without permission from a parent or guardian. If you are a parent or legal guardian and think your child under 13 has given us information, you can email us at [support@member.renttoown.org](mailto:support@member.renttoown.org). You can also write to us at the address listed at the end of this policy. Please mark your inquiries “COPPA Information Request.” Parents, you can learn more about how to protect children's privacy on-line [here.](https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/0031-protecting-your-childs-privacy-online)

## We store information in the United States.

Information we maintain may be stored both within and outside of the United States. If you live outside of the United States, you understand and agree that we may transfer your information to the United States. This site is subject to U.S. laws, which may not afford the same level of protection as those in your country.

## We use standard security measures.

The Internet is not 100% secure. We cannot promise that your use of our Platforms will be completely safe. We encourage you to use caution when using the Internet. This includes not sharing your passwords. To learn more about how to protect yourself online, visit www.ftc.gov.

We keep personal information as long as it is necessary or relevant for the practices described in this Policy. We also keep information as otherwise required by law.

## We may link to other sites or have third party services on our Platforms we don’t control.

Our Platforms may have links to websites we do not control. Our Platforms may also have plugins or host other third party services that we don’t control. This policy does not apply to the privacy practices of those websites or third parties. When you interact with those websites or third parties, they may collect information from you. Read the privacy policy of other websites carefully. We are not responsible for these third party practices.

## Feel free to contact us if you have more questions.

If you have any questions about this Policy, please email us at [support@member.renttoown.org](mailto:support@member.renttoown.org).

You can also write to us or call at:

RentToOwn.org   
1900 Powell Street, #600   
Emeryville, CA 94608   
(888) 556-3889 

If you have any questions about this Policy or want to correct or update your information, please email us at [support@member.renttoown.org](mailto:support@member.renttoown.org).

## We may update this Policy.

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time, but the changes will not apply retroactively.

We will notify you of any material changes to our Policy as required by law. We will also post an updated copy on our website (RentToOwn.org). Please check our website periodically for updates.

© 2017 RentToOwn.org. All rights reserved.
